Contact

+971 502184568

khajeerak29@gmail.com

Dubai, UAE

hajeerakhanum (LinkedIn)

Notice period: 30 days

Top Skills

HTML, CSS

JavaScript

React.js

MERN Stack

GitHub

MongoDB

AWS

Java SpringBoot

Python Programming

Restful APIs

PHP

MySQL

ASP.NET core

Node.js

Problem solving Skills

Team work

Excellent Communication

Certifications

JavaScript Essential Training React Native Essential Training

Languages

English

Arabic

Hindi

Hajeera Khanum

Full stack developer | 5+ Years of Innovation in Tech

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Summary

As a Senior Software Engineer at Al Jazira Poultry Farm (owned by **Al Ain Farms**), a prominent name in the food and beverage industry, I have played a pivotal role in shaping and advancing technology initiatives at my organization with over 5+ years of experience and a **Master's degree** in Computer Science Engineering.

My core competencies include UI/UX front end development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and frameworks like React.js, Vue or Angular. Back-end technologies such as Node.js, Express.js,. Integrate with MySQL and third-party APIs databases and version control systems like Git. Strong understanding of software development lifecycle (SDLC) and Agile methodologies

Scalable back-end services and APIs using technologies like Node.js, Python, Ruby, Java and PHP. Experience with RESTful APIs and web services. As a Technical Lead and Full Stack Developer, I have also demonstrated my ability to design and work in an Agile/Scrum development process, develop, and maintain web applications from concept to deployment.

Experience

Al Jazira Poultry Farm

Full Stack developer

Nov 2023 - Present (1 years 7 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Achieved remarkable results in multiple key areas such as:

- -.Develop robust and scalable back-end services and APIs using technologies like Node.js, Python, Ruby, Java and PHP.
- -Front-end UI/UX development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and frameworks like Angular and React.
- -Integrate with MSSQL and third-party APIs databases.
- -Design, develop, and maintain web applications from concept to deployment.
- -Understanding with version control systems like Git.

Page 1 of 2

- -Clear, efficient and maintainable coding for websites.
- -Perform debugging, unit testing, and code reviews.
- -Preserve and enhance security, scalability, and performance of website.
- -Experience with RESTful APIs and web services.

Hudini

Senior Fullstack Developer

May 2021 – Aug 2023 (2 years 3 months) Bengaluru, India

- API integration for the payment gateway
- Custom Backend Module Development
- Deploy the projects into the server
- Website Chat Application Development using Node js, WebSocket, HTML and JavaScript
 - Ecommerce project development using NodeJs, ExpressJs , ReactJs, Redux and MongoDB
 - Developed the application to collect e-commerce websites product details for marketplace using PYTHON- 3, BeatifulSoap etc

KPIT Technologies

Full Stack Developer

Jan 2020 – May 2021 (1 years 4 months) Bengaluru, India

Projects I have worked:

https://www.iclothing.com/ https://www.vetus.com/ https://www.linenfabrics.co.uk/

PSD to HTML conversion and integrate into the projects.

Deploy the projects into the server

Education

Visvesvaraya Technological University, India

Master's degree (M.Tech), Computer Science & Engineering

(GATE Scholar) (2020 - 2022)

Visvesvaraya Technological University, India Bachelor's Degree (B.Tech), Computer science & Engineering (2016 - 2020)